It's great to be with Elliot Cherry and
Michael Keller. Uh Elliot is married to
Brida and uh the pastor of 12 South in
Nashville in the Midtown group, I guess.
Yep. And Michael uh is married to Sarah
and uh he is the pastor of the Redeemer
Lincoln um square church in Manhattan.
And what part of Manhattan? Lincoln
Square, I guess. But um in the Lincoln
Square area which is near Lincoln Center
which is our art center. It's uh in the
60s over on the west side. Very good. So
uh tell me about your families. Uh I
just mentioned your wife's names.
Elliot, you go first. Yeah. Uh yeah, my
wife's name is Brida. We've been
married. This is our 16th year of
wedding. Uh or I'm sorry, it's our 15th
wedding anniversary entering our 16th
year of marriage. um in a couple months.
And uh yeah, we got five kids in
Nashville. Uh two, four, seven, 10, and
12, I think. Uh four girls and a boy.
And um yeah, we love life in N. Life in
Nashville is good. Family life is good.
What you said, we've got five kids in
Nashville. I thought you were going to
say an eight in Ohio, you know, or
something like that. I think around
five. when you have about five kids,
like you start, like you said, I think.
You hear that? I I love the fact that
that means Elliot when he gets older is
gonna really be like, I don't know.
Like, I have no idea what their ages
are. I'm already I'm already like this.
Um, yeah, we have four girls and a boy
and uh it's chaos. Chaos all the time,
but it's good. It's good chaos. So, good
trouble.
How about you, Michael?
Uh, I have I guess it's was it 2025? Uh
I got married in O2 November 25
no 20 it's it's the year of 2025 of our
Lord and uh I got married in 2002 so I
guess it's uh 23 24 years of marriage
and um got married out of college. I
have two girls 14 and 12. So one just
graduated from 8th grade. So I have a
high schooler just now. And um yeah,
we've been we lived we've lived in the
city. Started did an RUF here uh back in
uh I guess 2009. Did that for seven
years. And I've been started a new
Redeemer Lincoln Square uh site. I guess
it's not new anymore. It's eight years.
We're eight years into this. So that's
hard to believe. Katherine, I had the um
joy of being at your fifth anniversary
and that was a great celebration and I
can't believe that's been three years.
Um Uh, incidentally, uh, Michael Elliott
and I have the, uh, privilege of being
in a group together that meets annually.
Uh, Ray Cortis started it and we've been
to Scotland and to Utah and mostly to
Nashville.
So, um, each year it's just a great
reunion and it's great to see you guys
today. Yeah, man. I'm gonna ask
questions. You answer how you want and
if you want to go off the beaten path,
uh, feel free. Either way, this is going
to be reduced to about 30 seconds
anyway, so it doesn't matter. But,
um, so, how did you guys become friends?
Oh, are we friends? Wait, wait,
that's a little bit too strong of a
term. I thought we were here to talk
about Yeah, I don't know. Uh, so I It
needs to be stated that I was actually
in the group first, Mike's group, the
group he's referring to. So, I was asked
to be in the group first before Michael
was asked to be in the group. Uh, but it
was really really a sweet thing about
friendship and um about how it formed
because
um we met in this group many years ago
and there was a really fast connection
honestly over like laughter and humor
over some like immature texts that were
being sent back and forth, some gifs and
memes that were being shared during the
group. I was like, "Oh, uh, we find the
same things funny." And then come to
find out, we're both middle of three
boys. Uh, both the only boy of the of
our siblings, our family of origin, that
entered ministry and both, uh, sons of
ministry parents. Um, Michael's parents
are a little bit more wellknown than my
parents, but it was the same kind of
dynamic of like grew up in a ministry
house, didn't think I'd ever be in
ministry. Lord clearly called us both to
ministry. We get the middle brother
birth order thing. We get the like we're
young pastors trying to figure this out
thing and we're in this group with so
many wiser older brothers who have been
ahead of us that we really connected.
We're the young guys in the group that
you were talking about. So it really it
was so fast the first night even that we
all went to dinner and he and I rode
back together. Uh it was like oh we have
so many things in common. Um, I think
this is going to be this this is more
than just like we'll see each other once
a year. Um, this will be a fast
friendship. We didn't know what it'd
become, but it it became really really
sweet early. What Elliot's trying to say
is is that the group had a lot of folks
who had been in ministry for a long
time, and the least mature and the
youngest people were both me and him. We
were actually the youngest ones. But
that's not enough. like just because
you're the same age and stuff. I think
uh there's you know you hear that I
think CS Lewis has that famous you know
famous phrase that sort of the the part
of the opening of a friendship the
beginning of a friendship is where you
know two people are like you know you
two like as well like wait wait wait you
we're wait we're actually aligned on
this and uh it it's it's where yes
friendships have to be built but I think
they're also discovered and Um, I think
there was a discovery for both Ellie and
I. Both of us have been in ministry long
enough to know that we look around at
other people doing ministry and this is
the benefit of a cohort that we were in.
We got to see like, oh, that's one that
person has this gift and that's why
they're doing ministry that way and and
this person has that personality and
that's why they're doing it this way.
And when we met each other, we're like,
"Oh, there's somebody here." I never met
somebody I think I honestly say this
that I um that had so many parallels of
of how they think and act, both good and
bad. Say, "Uh, oh, you too. Okay, I get
you." And and the fact that I think
Elliot, one time a couple months ago,
you said the fact that you're in
ministry doing it this way means I can
be in ministry and do it this way. And I
think there was something really really
beautiful that that came out of that.
Yeah, there was not just a kinship early
on in our friendship, but a like and the
me too, the you two CS Lewis stuff, but
like a um I think we give each other
freedom to be ourselves and to believe
like it's okay to be a pastor and be
this way because there can be certain
pastor groups that you get into, not
necessarily ours, Mike, but like certain
pastor rooms where you're like, I don't
really fit here. I'm I don't know that
this is like I feel outside of the box
on the way that I think about things or
the way that I want to act. And some of
that's immature and some of that is
like, oh, but kind of giving each other
the the joy of the like, you can I can
really be really me around Mike as we're
talking about being pastors, as we're
talking about being um dads and bosses
and husbands, and I think vice versa,
the freedom of like, man, this it gives
me it just it's it was a deep intimacy
of like we get to be ourselves around
each other in a in a world of being a
pastor. So, um, yeah, it it it was fast,
but it has gone really deep even though
it began pretty quick, um, on the
connection level. I don't sort of Oh,
were you going to say something, Mike?
No, no, you go first, Mike. I was, you
know, just kind of going based on what
you guys are saying, have there been
moments that you can remember where
you've had to challenge the other one
where uh you've you've felt like uh God
used that person to even speak hard
truth into your life, that kind of
thing. What's what's happened with the
friendship along those lines? Well,
yeah. I mean I real friendship again
back to the discovery aspect. I think
you can have lots of friends which are
really acquaintances. I think there's a
level of friendship where there's not
many of them and I don't think I think
you can count friends that have the
depth of relationship where you can uh
where you grant persons license to
actually speak in each other's life. Uh
I used to you know I tell people in my
church I'm like you have the ability to
speak into somebody's life to the degree
that they've given you access to speak
into their life. you want to call
somebody out. Yeah. Okay. And you you
can there's a way to do that actually
where you don't have the relationship
because for the name of in the name of
justice. But if you actually want
traction with somebody, do can you say
something hard to someone where even if
they disagree with you, they actually
still know that you mean it out of a
place of love? Yeah. That's only there's
only a small number of those people that
you have in your life. And I think uh
both Ellie and I have just over the over
the years developed that say, "Yeah, you
have that you have that access. speak
into it and and say things and and we I
mean I've got Yeah, Mike, when you just
said that, I've got multiple examples
between us where that's not what he just
said is not hypothetical, it's actual.
Um last summer I was going through a
really hard time ministerally and
professionally.
And Mike Michael and I talk regularly,
not we don't have like a scheduled call
or anything, but we we're texting, we're
calling, we're playing online chess with
each other, and he's usually beating me
at that, but we're we're always in
conversation to some degree. And I
called him because I was like, "Dude, I
got to let you in on some things that
are going on." And he didn't just
uh show compassion as to what some
things that I was facing ministerally
that were really hard and lonely. Um he
he rebuked me like dude here here's what
love would look like for you to choose
to treat this person this way and here
that's going to cost you to love. So
like let me give you the courage which
is encouragement. Um let me give you the
courage to go love this way and it's
you're going to suffer uh for it. And it
was like man yeah it what I mean what he
just said but it's proverbs that talks
about wounds from a friend that can be
trusted. It was like yeah I don't really
want to hear that. I kind of would have
rather just call you and have you tell
me how hard my life is and make me feel
good about that. But it was like, no,
this is actually what you need to go do.
And I remember three or four years ago,
too, um, when when his dad was going
through cancer treatments. Um, I
remember his wife Sarah was was really
sad and scared and, uh,
not sure that Michael was like uh, you
know, doing okay. Doing okay. Yeah.
Yeah, I want to I want to protect the
confidentiality of some things that
Sarah shared, but basically called me
and said, "I need you to call my husband
because I'm not sure he's going to
listen to anybody else except you." Um,
that's great. And so, yeah, that kind of
stuff, it doesn't it doesn't just uh
grow a friendship, it confirms the
friendship like, "Oh, we can do this and
I'm not afraid, nothing's at stake
here." Um, so it's really Yeah, that's
that's a very real part of of the
friendship. But but to what I was saying
earlier, we both had given previously
each other license to do that where the
reason why I was able to do it like like
that what you just talked about it was
because you have in previous times.
Yeah. Where I didn't necessarily ask for
it. There's one thing. Hey, is there
something you want to talk to me about?
Like that's one thing. There's another
thing saying, "You know what? I didn't
ask for this moment, but you you do this
thing, Elliot, where you're like,
Michael, no, but Mike, Michael, like you
really like make me sit with something
and I like because you because there's
so many different ways the pastor can go
like that way and that way." And you're
like, "Nope, nope. Nope. This is what
we're doing." Yeah. This is what we're
doing. I think that um
I don't know if it's a spiritual gift or
not, but sarcasm, the Lord has given us
the ability to do that. Um really really
it might be might be I don't think it's
a fruit of the spirit. Maybe it's a gift
of the spirit that Paul forgot to list
but um I think I think it was one of
them. I just get into that. Yeah there
is a like and there have actually been
some recent even sociological studies
that have shown that like giving friends
hard times like poking fun making fun.
No I know I saw the study it was
actually or maybe we talked about it. I
can't remember who showed what, but
yeah, to the degree that you can tease
somebody that's actually a friend,
that's the depth of the of the
friendship. It's amazing study. So, I
think so much teasing that does go on
and Kangjen, you've witnessed it when
we've all been staying in the same
cabin.
Sometimes it's like annoying for
everybody else but like brothers but
there is this sense of like no we can do
this because there's this other thing
underneath that like there we've gone so
deep with each other in joy and in grief
and in challenge that it's like us
poking fun of each other is actually
just like proof of how deep this thing
is. Um, so something we were together in
Scotland last year speaking at some
different things together trying to
encourage some European missionaries and
some Scottish church planters and it was
really I mean like what is our life that
we get to go do that together and we
we've heard great things about that by
the way. Thanks. Who did you hear more
good stuff about? Yeah. Yeah. Was what
exactly who was praised more? Was it me?
It was obvious to them that you guys
knew me, but I I don't want to get into
the details of that. Actually, I don't
know if that's good for you that they
knew that, but um but we were we were
doing this thing. It was actually a
really sweet moment for our friendship
because we were doing like this panel
discussion and one Q&A. Yeah. And one of
one of the we were bantering and poking
fun at each other and then trying to
answer some like missional theological
questions and and it was it was a joy.
But then after the after after the Q&A
time, one of the elders from the the
church there who's a very, you know,
widely respected scholar in Scotland
came up to us and say he said, "Hey, my
son um was asking me after like, "Hey,
Dad, Michael and Elliot up there, they
they were treating each other like they
weren't best friends, but it was obvious
that they were best friends. They didn't
talk to each other like best friends."
Wait, wait. I thought it was I thought
it was like, "Hey, Dad, do you have
somebody who treats you like an enemy,
but really is your friend?" I thought it
was It was something like that. And he's
like, "I saw Michael and Elliot talk to
each other like enemies, but clearly
they were best friends." And it was like
this little nine-year-old's observation
of like how they how close they are. And
the dad was like, "I don't know if I do
have anyone like that." And so there was
a sweetness of like even I I hope you
know the hope is is that people can tell
how much we love each other and that's
not that's not for show. There is a deep
a deep connection. It's very evident and
and you know Cortis and I have enjoyed
that for ever and um I just feel sorry
for people who don't have that. Yeah.
Because Mike, Mike, for you and for you
and Ray, was it like discovered? Like,
how did you like what what was it for
you and Ray? What what was that like?
Uh, you know, it um in
the the funniest little experience, we
worked out together. Um we we've known
each other since junior high and then uh
we were on the same basketball team and
towards the end of our school year, our
high school years, we worked out
together and just laughed a lot. Um I
went to his house after work on Sundays
and um we made dinner together, then
went to church that night together,
listened to comedy albums, uh get any
good hints, pickups, you know, but yeah.
Um, but just uh them roommates in
college and and uh some years apart and
together was very organic. Um, have you
and Ray ever been ministerally,
pastorally in the same city? We've never
been. Uh, we we had one opportunity
where maybe we could have but didn't.
But um but I I would just say that it
was all those and then
finding that safe space to share really
deep painful
and hard things together. Yeah. And to
work through them and to walk with the
other through them. Just just to speak
to that, Mike, because I bet there's
some people listening going, "Man, yeah.
I mean, you just said, man, I feel bad
for people who don't have this." I think
there's a lot of people who don't
because to be honest, I'm in my 40s. I
didn't have this until I kind of met
Elliot. And so, and I I do think these
are very rare relationships. Like, you
can count them on one hand if you have
them uh at all. And and you'd be lucky
you have one. It'd be great if you have
more than that. And some people do. They
can have they can some people have five,
whatever. But it's not usually more than
that. If you're listening and you you're
saying that like, well, how do I you
can't just say, I'm going to meet
somebody to have a deep relationship. Um
again, I still have Lewis in my head
where it can't be you can't meet about
that. It has to be something that you
meet over. Yeah. There needs to be
something in common. So commonality is
one of those things that I think I
remember Lewis's quote is like it's it
can be dominoes, it can be mice, it can
be whatever, but you have to have
something where you connect over. You
say, "Yes, I want to do life with you
over this issue." And and so Ellie and I
have um you know, yeah, we're both in
ministry, but we also have chess. We
also have a lot of just there's multiple
reason. What's that game we played last
year? Katan, but that was Yeah, he lost.
What matters is he didn't he didn't win
as much as I did. That's all matters. Um
anyway, but my point is there's lots of
different So, who what do you do? You
need to find things that you have in
common with somebody else. There needs
to be some level of time. That takes
time, by the way. And a lot of people I
talk to these days, I'm like, they don't
have time. Well, the reason I don't have
time is because I believe friendship out
of all the relationships that are out
there is the least uh instinctual
because you have to have love to have to
you know procreate. You have to have uh
neighbor relationships to to make it in
life. You have to have work
relationships. I think a lot of times we
devalue friendship because friendship
becomes like a yeah like a luxury almost
that
you know some go as your alls did. You
you all talked about that dinner like it
was speed dating, you know. Yeah. But um
but I think there's a place where you
also um you take a little risk. Now we
grew up together so it just happened
over time but with you guys at some
point you made this this kind of uh
decision to step into each other's lives
and it could have gone wrong. Yeah. And
vulner vulnerability is vulnerability.
Yeah. And you can't you you kind of like
not that you're like dating, but there
is like a I'm going to take one step
further and you're going to take one
step further kind of to test the waters
like are we still good or is it still
good? And and something you said Michael
a second ago about time.
There is something that again I think we
discovered no we didn't plot out the
years at all. We we don't do good at
plotting things out. But there was a
sense of like some rituals that came in
terms of like in like an underlying
commitment to see each other, to be with
each other, to text, to call, to check
in. Again, not with any like iron fist
or rig uh rigid scheduling, but
intentionality and there's
intentionality and it takes time though.
And that that's I think because
friendship is a luxury potentially,
Michael. Like you were saying, we have
we have known the loneliness of
ministry. We have known the like the
grief of life. We have known the like
the the loneliness of being the young
senior pastor of churches that it's like
we don't know what we're doing, but the
Lord called us to this. Like those
things like, "Oh, I need this." So we
valued it. And the value of needing a
friendship like this even across state
lines was like, "But that's going to
take time." So like we stay together
with every year with each other at GA.
You come to Nashville every December.
You already were doing that with your
wife as like an annual overnight and you
know we we'll see each other. And then
it was like okay but we've got we got
our annual group together with Kangjen
and and Ray and those guys. There just
became a sense of like oh this the Lord
has like already set this up in some
ways. But we've also I mean there was a
stretch last year where we realized like
oh wait we've seen each other like 10
months in a row. We tried to make it 12.
Maybe we made it eight or nine. I don't
remember. And then I think I broke the
chain. It was my fault. But there was a
little bit of like, man, we we just
really want to see each other. And this
costs money and time. But like my wife
and I go to the city. We were just there
couple weeks ago, saw Mike and Sarah.
Like what? We're going to make the
effort to try to cultivate a friendship
because this doesn't just happen. and we
may go six months without seeing each
other, but we're going to there's
built-in things where we're going to
spend the cost. Yeah. Financially and
temporally to to make to keep this
cultivated. You know, as I'm listening
to you guys, I'm thinking about a group
that meets once a year. And in some
ways, your friendship with each other
makes our group better, too. You know,
and the other friendships that are in
there. It isn't just the two of you. And
and it and it takes me to your dad's
funeral, Michael. And I think that um
obviously we're honoring this man that
we think is amazing and has helped shape
us, but the truth is we sat together as
your friends. And we were just as proud
of you in that service as we were
honoring your dad's memory. Yeah. And
that made that very very special. It's
true. Um, so, uh, yeah, this thing
that's happening with you guys has
helped forge this other group that
wouldn't have been as tight into
something very special. Well, and I
think again, I think we we just
undervalue it. I'm I'm struggling with
this with with New Yorkers is they don't
realize how if we're made in God's image
and therefore there's there's aspects of
God that we actually can see in each
other if we actually relate to each
other. I think we undervalue that as a
as an office to
perceive and get into. It takes that
time and effort. And so in today's
business where we're always entertaining
and always looking and scrolling and
things just spending that time to and I
like what Elliot you said that just
takes that that effort, but it does it
multiplies out into not just our
relationship but then totally it really
does. And and you know, at the end of
your life,
um, and I'm closer to the end of my life
than you're at the end of your life, but
at the end of our lives, you're going to
look back on your friendship with each
other. Ray and I do a lot of reflecting
now. And and you're going to look back
and say there there weren't a ton of
friends that close. Yeah.
So, it's it's fortunate thing for a
person to be able to to find those
friendships. Yeah, that's good. Yeah.
And I think that there's like uh
my Michael my goal, you you're really
kind to think about like what what would
people Wait, which one's Mike? Which
one? Which one's Mike? Which one's
Michael? Well, I don't care. Um Okay.
You were just saying like people that
are watching or listening, I want to be
considerate of that that like people may
watch or listen and go, I don't have
that. I don't have an annual group that
meets and I wish I could give like a
formula for it. I mean the some of the
Louis stuff you're referencing from the
four loves is great on like it needs
these features which is true. I I
honestly I don't say this like to
overspiritualize it. The Lord did this.
The Lord brought us together when he did
the Lord over overlapped the lives. And
so and I don't say this flippantly in
any way but like to pray for it. Like
the Lord knew what we needed before we
asked but we both knew we needed it and
and like the Lord gave it and the Lord
gives good gifts. So there is like a ask
the Lord for it. I will say this what
what maybe we could be a hope for a
proof of it's not impossible to have
deep friendships
across the country. Um it's also not
it's not it doesn't mean you have to
talk every day. Sometimes we go weeks
without talking and but like right I
know the moment we see each other or
connect even if it's for five minutes on
the phone or for a couple hours in New
York like a few weeks ago it's like
we're gonna we're going to laugh. We're
going to go really deep. We're gonna
laugh some more. We're gonna go really
deep. We're gonna go in and out of that
space and like fill up the friendship
tank, you know, as as the story. But
Ellie, there you just get to me. I just
heard a formula. You need to spend time
with each other. That's true. Has to be
something in common. Yeah. You have to
be vulnerable at some level. Yes. Like
and and and teasing. Maybe that's a
cultural manifestation, but there
there's some level of intimacy and
attention and intention and fun where
we're actually saying, but there's a
costliness to that cuz time is costly,
vulnerability is costly. We're giving
each other access. But so there is
aspects to say that's what it would
take. But you're 100% right that like
just because you have all those things
doesn't turn it. It's like me with a you
put you can put flour and sugar and and
I and I still will mess it up. I still I
can have all the ingredients and it
doesn't mean I'm going to make something
beautiful. Right. Well, and I think what
Elliott said that's so important is
is that it's worthy
of having a vision for and praying
towards it. Yeah. You know, and and like
you said, God met you there with each
other. It's really wonderful. Yeah. any
well me a little bit more for Elliot
than Elliot for me just to be clear
because he's like he's just a couple
years older so he still feels like he
has something to offer me even though
I've been a senior pastor longer so I I
have some things I am a little more w
but I am wiser so it's just just it's
okay I I it it's part of who I am I I
see you all very much the same in
whatever I think of you
no you know the reality is that uh
you're you're too brilliant young men
that uh God is doing great things
through. Thanks. The fact that he's
given you each other is just a real
blessing. Yeah. And Michael, you know,
Jeff White's in our little circle now.
And fact, he and Ray were just up here a
few weeks ago. Uh I wouldn't trade these
friendships for anything. Yeah. And uh I
wish them on everybody. Yeah. You all
have collaborated some in in Scotland.
Any place else? Do you do you uh uh we
haven't we haven't spoken together it
well Mike has Michael sorry the I have
to distinguish Michael um this can be a
promo Michael Michael's written a book
he won't talk about it but he's written
a book uh co-written with his dad but he
wrote most of it um comes out early next
year and he let me into that I didn't
collaborate I'm not an editor or a
writer but he let me into that process
to get to put eyes on it early on rough
drafts and I've read most of it. It's
really good. Um I probably won't buy it
drafts, but both parts, Tim's and
Michael's or Yes. Well, I only I only
edited Michael's parts, but um I would
say the other thing we've gotten to
collaborate on, and this is real, is is
pastoral stuff like organizational
things, building things, staff things,
preaching things. We collaborate on
sermons. We listen to each other's
sermons, one for encouragement, but also
to steal stuff where it's like, "Hey, by
the way, I was I was talking to somebody
on the phone. I'm not going to tell you
who it is, but she was like, "I was
listening to Elliot's sermon and I was
talking about joy and joy is this. It's
not happiness. It's" and I was like,
"That's my stuff." And she's like, "No,
no, no. I don't think so. Elliot really
did a good job with it." And I said,
"Wait a second." And then I'm like,
"It's not important. It's not important.
Don't split hairs. It's not important."
Elliot I was like, "But actually, it was
Elliot's uh just way way of doing it."
cuz she actually listened to a lot of
stuff that I was doing on Joy because uh
we're we're collaborating and so it's
just it's just fun to hear her
listening. We really do. And that we'll
text stuff about like, "Hey, have you
ever preached on this?" And I'll go
listen to his sermon to help get my mind
going. And there is there is like real
world applicable skill collaboration on
it too. That's fun. Um he's got tons of
great resources. I've like he does this
leadership training thing on Sunday
nights. Is it catalyst? Is that what
it's called? Whatever it is where it's
like Yeah. like, hey, I need all I need
that eightweek material or 12week
material, whatever it is, because I need
to look through it for my own stuff.
Like, swapping of ideas on like a honing
the craft of this job. We do that a lot.
His website stinks. So, I'm always like,
"Bro, I'm trying to find out what what
have you preached on? How have you done
this?" Uh, we're getting we're getting a
new website in like six weeks. It'll
it'll launch. It's hard to believe that
like what 10,000 people go to his church
every Sunday. I know. I know. But I'm
like I'm trying to get I'm trying to
actually learn from you, man. I just
can't find the information. That was a
bug. Thank you. Well, and it's I'm
trying to say it's such good stuff. I
was trying to find it. I have to like
actually call the guy up and say,
"Please show me where it is." Catching
up. Here's here's Yeah, it we're having
to deal with that, too. Yeah. Um here
here's a question. Does the fact that uh
LA you're in Nashville, Michael, you're
in New York. Um, does that in any way
help you in in speaking wisdom into the
other's ministry at all? Yeah, my my
city's better than his, but what what
else were you trying to say? Oh my gosh.
See, yeah, that's Yeah, that's so wise
to speak like that. Yeah. Um
certainly on all the like I think
because he did college ministry for so
long, not just in New York, but like the
like current generation of things and
you know Gen Z that's coming right
behind it, but like what do people care
about now and how do you kind of speak
the language of the time like Paul where
it's like I'm trying to like in Acts 17
like I'm trying to speak the language of
the culture so that they'll listen to
what I have to say about Jesus. Mhm.
He's great on that stuff. And obviously
New York is is the epicenter of that. I
I will say culturally, we deal with
really similar people, young driven,
similar idols, similar upbringings in
some ways. But I have a lot to learn
from him on I think New York's probably
five or 10 years ahead of where
Nashville is on certain cultural things
that like But I'll put I'll push back on
that just a little bit because because
of what social media has done, which is
flattened culture a lot. A lot of the
things that I'm dealing with is a lot of
the same very same things that you're
dealing with, uh, Elliot. And yeah, and
therefore we actually have there's a
common language that's actually
developing. There used to be a lot more
lo locality. There's still distinctives.
Don't don't get me wrong. There's
distinct idols. There's distinct
contextual issues that we do talk about
like, well, you do it this way, but I
have to do it that way. But there
actually is a lot more commonality than
I think these days than there used to be
because of what social media has done.
That's true. That's true. Very good.
Yeah. Um um we're probably gonna have to
wrap it up soon, but um anything you all
want to add? Anything you would do to
encourage I I just say this not to be uh
morbid, but um you know, one of you guys
is going to probably preach the other's
funeral one day, man.
We haven't actually I hadn't thought
about that. What do you Mike? What is
You tell me. What is that? What's that?
I just think it's a beautiful reality.
Um, you know, Ray and I, one of us will
probably preach, the others or speak at
this uh funeral that that God's given us
something to take all the way to the
announcement that that that the other uh
lives because of the resurrected Christ
and our friendship fuels that to some
extent. So, man, um, that's here's what
I'll here's what I'll say about that.
This is where my I don't think it's ADD.
I think it's where the spirit just took
my imagination. Mhm. I could be ADD
still, but whatever. Could be spirit can
could spirits who made me add ADD. So,
you got a problem with it. Take it up
with him. But I think that um man, when
I hear you say that, Kangjen, here's
where my here's where my heart went. Uh
so, a few days after his dad died, I
flew the city to be with him.
We drank whiskey and bourbon on his
rooftop till very late on that um on
that night and in the days following. Um
and then he left town um to go get away,
which was great. But I remember like I'm
just so sad that my friend's sad that he
lost his dad. Um I was so sad with him.
I was so sad for him. And and we and it
was intimate. Um
here's what I just thought of when you
said doing each other's funerals. I
wasn't even presuming that I would like
be the guy that would preach his
funeral. Maybe there's a lot of people
that would want to preach at his funeral
and friends of his parents and other
mentors like people. I I I would not
presume that I'll be the guy to preach
at his funeral. I know I'll be really
sad at his funeral. That's what I
thought of like I we will all miss one
another when it comes to those friends.
Yeah. And be profound. So I I would I
would be honored too. I just when you
just said of the other's funeral, I just
thought, man, I'll be so sad when he's
gone. That's all I could think of. Not
if I get to speak it or not. That was be
sad. I think one of the unique things
being pastors and a lot of what we talk
about is Jesus and because we think
Jesus is uh not just an idea or just,
you know, an example, but Jesus's
savior.
um when kind of knowing that that's
actually at the heart, even if we're not
very good at putting it at the core of
our hearts, knowing that that's a a
desire to have that desire. I think it's
going to be um a beautiful thing if when
and if to be able to speak about Jesus
and how Jesus is um you know, saw Jesus
in that friend, what Jesus did and what
and how we saw Jesus and how we see
again God through. I I that that would
be a great honor because friendship is
one of those chosen relationships. Like
you don't you don't get to choose your
dad. You don't get to choose your mom.
You have to be you have to be in
relationship with them no matter what.
And uh yes, you get to choose a spouse
kind of. Um but I think your friends is
one of those beautiful potential
possibilities to be able to then if you
hold on to them over decades and decades
to speak some beautiful words. if I can
if I have to be the one if I can
actually say it get it out gutturally
from the tears but um but I think it
could really be a beautiful thing. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Anything else you guys want
to add in this? Any LA, you know, last
shots you want to take at each other or
We'll save that for after the recording
stops. We'll let
you guys did a great job. You are Thanks
for asking. You're great pastors and uh
your friendship is precious.